ergoresources.org 2008-09-18

# AAOHN Online Privacy Statement

**AAOHN Online Privacy Statement**

|   
---|---  
  
 **Your Privacy is Important  
** Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy, we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used.

**Information Collection and Use  
** This notice applies to all information collected or submitted on the [www.aaohn.org](http://www.aaohn.org/) Web site. AAOHN is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. It is necessary to be a member of AAOHN to use some parts of this Web site and to receive a more personalized experience. Demographic information and unique identifiers (such as social security numbers or licensures) are not shared with outside parties. Postal mailing addresses, but not phone numbers or e-mail addresses, are sometimes provided to organizations that have information or services relevant to occupational health nursing for the sole purpose of allowing those organizations to share that information with members. AAOHN reviews all such information before sharing member addresses.

**Orders**  
We request information from the user on our order form. Here a user must provide contact information (i.e. name and shipping address) and financial information (i.e. credit card number and expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill the customer’s orders. If we have trouble processing an order, this contact information is used to get in touch with the user. We use the information you provide about yourself when placing an order only in the context of your involvement with AAOHN. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete an order you place. 

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s hard drive containing information about the user. Use of a cookie saves members the step of entering a username and password and allows members to receive personalized information on the site. For instance, by setting a cookie on our site, the member would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use our site by entering a username and password each time the member visits the site. 

**Log Files**  
We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track links between pages, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

**Our Commitment to Data Security  
** This Web site takes every precaution to protect our users’ information. To prevent unauthorized access; maintain data accuracy; and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. 

When our order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number), that information is encrypted and protected with Secure Socket Layer (SSL) software. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when you are just “surfing.”

**Links**  
This Web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that AAOHN is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.

How You Can Update or Correct Your Information   
You can access all your personally identifiable information using the member information page on this site or by contacting AAOHN Member Services at [memberservices@aaohn.org](mailto:custservice@aaohn.org) or (770) 455-7757. If you have concerns regarding the use of your information, please contact AAOHN Member Services.

**Choice/Opt-out**  
We send all new members a welcoming e-mail to verify username and password. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, or a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our members, we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Members are given the opportunity to “opt-out” of having their information used for non-AAOHN purposes. Members may also opt-out of receiving AAOHN e-mail newsletter communications. Define your opt-out preferences using the member information page on this site or by contacting AAOHN Member Services at [memberservices@aaohn.org](mailto:custservice@aaohn.org) or (770) 455-7757.

**How To Contact Us**   
Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please contact us at [memberservices@aaohn.org](mailto:custservice@aaohn.org) or (770) 455-7757.
